Guide to the Paul and Kitty Baker Papers
The Wittliff Collections
- Scripts, 1959-1992, undated
  - Wolfe, Thomas Of Time and the River, a dramatization by the Baylor Theater, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Yelvington, Ramsey Cloud of Witnesses, prepared by Paul Baker, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 3)
- The Baylor Children's Theater Early Development, 1966-1985, undated
  This series contains materials compiled by Kitty Baker about the early development of The Baylor Children's Theater. In 1941, Mrs. Baker began a children's art and drama class for the Baker's first daughter and her friends, which would eventually grow into the Baylor Children's Theater. In this series, clippings, photographs, booklets, workshop materials and ephemera record the activities of the Children's Theater and Mrs. Baker's role as its co-founder.
  - Ms. Kitty Baker's materials on early development of the Baylor Children's Theater, 1966-1985, undated (Box 15, Folder 4-5)
  - 3-ring binder with materials on early development of the Baylor Children's Theate, 1966-1985, undated (Box 22)
- Clippings, 1942-1990, undated
  The small group of clippings in this series highlights periods in Paul Baker's life from his undergraduate years at Trinity University in Waxahachie, TX, to his work at Baylor University, and his retirement in Waelder, TX.
  - San Antonio Light, August 5, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous clippings, 1942-1990, undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Framed clipping about the Dallas Theater Center which was designed by Frank Lloyd Wright, undated (Box 21)
- Theater Brochures and Programs, 1929-1996, undated
  The brochures and programs in this series come mostly from theaters and productions with which Paul Baker was involved either as a performer or director. They are arranged alphabetically by theater name.
  - Dallas Theater Center brochures, 1929-1996, undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Trinity University Theater brochures, 1929-1996, undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous theater brochures, 1929-1996, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Iceland Base Command World War II, 1943-1945, undated
  Paul Baker collected the material in this series during his time as Special Service Entertainment Officer at Iceland Base Command in World War II. The Iceland Base Command newspaper, "The White Falcon," contains several articles about productions directed by Paul Baker at the base. Also included in this series are programs from some of these plays, as well as art works from Iceland. This series is arranged by material type.
  - Copies of the Iceland Base Command newspaper, "The White Falcon," and an Icelandic newspaper, "Morgunbladid", 1943-1945, undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Artworks, 1943-1945, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Play programs and ephemera, 1943-1945, undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Photographs, undated
  This series contains nine studio proofs of Paul and Kitty Baker. Additional photographs can be found in the Scrapbooks series.
  - Nine black and white, three and a half by five-inch studio proofs of Paul and Kitty Baker, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Personal Ephemera, 1911-1942, undated
  This series is made up of handwritten notes, commencement programs from Trinity and other Universities, booklets about foreign missionary work, calling cards and other assorted ephemera. The material is arranged by material type.
  - Handwritten notes, 1911-1942, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Trinity University and assorted university material, 1911-1942, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Books and Periodicals, 1953-1994, undated
  The material in this series pertains to theater and education, and much of it is by or about Paul Baker. Annotated or unpublished titles have been filed with in this series, other titles as listed have been cataloged below.
  The following titles have been cataloged separately:
  Baker, Paul The Drama Review: Architecture/Environment, with article "Flexible Theatrical Space," 1968. PN 1601 .T8
  :Baker, Paul Making Sense with Five Senses: The Motivation Force to Energize Learning. 1993. LB1067 .B35 1994
  Baylor University Institute for Oral History Oral Memoirs of Paul and Kitty Baker: A Series of Interviews Conducted 25 July 1990. PS3552.A433 Z465 1997
  Baylor University Institute for Oral History The Paul Baker Festival Second Harvest: Oral Memoirs of Students, Colleagues, and Family of Paul Baker. 1990. PS3552.A433 Z55 1997
  Byers, Ruth Creating Theater: From idea through performance with children and teens, 1968. PN3157 .B9 1968
  Cory, Joyce Burke The Dallas Theater Center: An Idea That Was Big Enough. 1980. PN2277.D22 D34 1980
  Dallas Theater Center Dallas Theater Center 1959-1979: Twenty Dynamic Years. 1979. PN2277.D22 D3 1979
  Dallas Theater Center Dallas Theater Center 1959-1994: Thirty-fifth Anniversary. 1994. PN2277.D22 D33 1994
  Flynn, Robert and Susan Russell When I Was Just Your Age: Remarkable Reflections On Growing Up In Another Era. 1992. E169 .F64 1992
  McRae, John M. Image 4 with article "Dramatic Experience: The Play and the Building" by Paul Baker 1966. NA1 .I451964
  O'Bannon, Ernest Venture: The Baylor Literary Quarterly, Winter 1953-1954. AP2 .V46 O'Neil, Ford Lessons in Looking: Dialogues with O'Neil Ford, Architect, Learning About Learning Artist/Teacher Series. 1981. NA2555 .F673 19
  - Baker, Paul ABCs of Natural Sensory Abilities Program Handbook (Preliminary Copy), Waelder Independent School District, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 10-11)
  - Baker, Paul American Stars (unpublished script), undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Stecker, Elizabeth Wear The Baylor Theater Method of Work – Excerpts From the Thesis: The Method of Work of the Baylor Theater with a Critical Analysis of the Prodcution of Othello, undated (Box 17, Folder 2)